Guide to the Time Inc. Time Publishing and Business Records 1929-1999 MS 3009-RG 24
New-York Historical Society
- Series IV. Promotion and Public Affairs Department Records, 1955-1999; 155.1 Linear feet in 156 record cartons, 1 document case, and 2 flat boxes
  - Subseries IV.I. Bio Files, 1951-1977; 1 Linear feet in 1 record carton
    - Rodin, Charles A., 1966 (Offsite-box 3249, Folder 115)
    - Scott, John M., undated (Offsite-box 3249, Folder 116)
    - Seamon, Richard M., 1969 (Offsite-box 3249, Folder 117)
    - Sinclair, Christopher, undated (Offsite-box 3249, Folder 118)
    - Symington, Garey, undated (Offsite-box 3249, Folder 119)
    - Taylor, Ricardo, 1966-1967 (Offsite-box 3249, Folder 120)
    - Thomas, John C., Jr., undated (Offsite-box 3249, Folder 121)
    - Thompson, Carleton, undated (Offsite-box 3249, Folder 122)
    - Valk, Gary, undated (Offsite-box 3249, Folder 123)
    - Waddill, John, 1955 (Offsite-box 3249, Folder 124)
    - Westerfield, Putney [empty], undated (Offsite-box 3249, Folder 125)
    - Wiedemann, George, undated (Offsite-box 3249, Folder 126)
    - Wilhelm, John, undated (Offsite-box 3249, Folder 127)
    - Womer, Mike, 1967 (Offsite-box 3249, Folder 128)
    - Zorthian, Barry, undated (Offsite-box 3249, Folder 129)
  - Subseries IV.J. Event Files, 1962-1990; 32 Linear feet in 33 record cartons
    The Event Files include files from Time Public Affairs and Promotion staff on the planning and implemetion of events, both for internal participation and events that invited outside guests. Events include anniversaries of the magazine; award ceremonies; conferences; seminars; dinners and lunches honoring special visitors; parties and receptions; presentations and other talks. There are also files that collected information on Henry Luce's funeral and other memorial events. Certain events are described in more detail within the container list.
    These files either have no known specific creator or including materials from several people within the department. Staff represented include Public Affairs directors Robert "Bob" Sweeney and Robert Ankerson; associate director Stan Kapner; general promotion manager Lane Fortinberry; special events manager Irina Bagration; Trade Publicity Manager Rita Robinson; and Public Affairs and Promotion staff Nancy Hall Megan, Julia Fay and Bill Baring-Gould. There are also some materials from staff outside of Public Affairs such as ad sales manager Robert Gordon and ad sales staff Reginald Brack.
    Organized alphabetically by event title then chronologically if an event occurred annually, then alphabetically within each year's event.
    - Anniversaries: 40th, 1962-1963 (Offsite-box 2852, Folder 3-23)
      The celebration for Time's 40th anniversary was a dinner at the Waldorf Astoria in Manhattan including almost 300 cover subjects as distinguished guests. Records include booklets listing the cover subject guests and containing messages from the United States President and Vice President, guest lists, invitations, a description of the film of the dinner, copies of the program and seating list, and speech transcipts.
      Half of the materials were found loose along with the Henry Luce funeral material and needed to be foldered, and half are copies pulled from Archives and may have been reference for a later anniversary. Since it wasn't clear if this was the use, these materials are included here.
    - Anniversaries: 40th, 1962-1963 (Offsite-box 2853, Folder 1-22)
    - Anniversaries: 40th and 50th, 1963, 1971 (Offsite-box 2853, Folder 23-24)
    - Anniversaries: [45th]: Cover Subjects List, 1967 (Offsite-box 2853, Folder 25)
    - Anniversaries: 50th, 1973 (Offsite-box 2854, Folder 1-14)
      The celebration for Time's 50th anniversary was a dinner at the Waldorf Astoria in Manhattan and the production of a commemorative coin. Records include planning for the coin, dinner invitations, and correspondence with John Secondari Productions commissioning a film.
      2 audiotape reels: analog; 7 in., 1/4 in. tape. On container: "50th Anniversary speeches (transcript in file drawer)." On label: "Time Magazine Tape #1 G__ 22-73 Waldorf Astoria."
    - Anniversaries: 60th, 1982-1983 (Offsite-box 2854, Folder 15-20)
      The celebrations for Time's 60th anniversary were a cruise and gala on the Queen Elizabeth II for special guests and select staff along with a brunch at Tavern on the Green for other staff. Records include invitation lists, notes from planning meetings, printed programs, and boarding arrangements.
    - Anniversaries: 60th, 1982-1983 (Offsite-box 2943, Folder 1-21)
    - Anniversaries: 60th [RESTRICTED], 1981-1983 (Offsite-box R56)
    - Awards: Thomas Jefferson Award, 1970-1971 (Offsite-box 2943, Folder 22-25)
      This award is given to Armed Forces journalists by the Department of Defense. The 1971 awards dinner was sponsored by Time.
    - Awards: Time College Achievement Award, 1989-1990 (Offsite-box 2851, Item 9-14)
      1 videocassette (VHS) (67 min.): 1/2 in. On label: "Award Ceremony. April 3, 1989. Sponsored by Volkswagen - U.S."
      1 videocassette (U-matic): sound; 3/4 in. On label: "Time College Achievement Award. 1989. Reel 1."
      1 videocassette (U-matic): sound; 3/4 in. On label: "Time College Achievement Awards 1989. Reel 2."
      1 videocassette (U-matic): sound; 3/4 in. On label: "Tape #1. 1990. Time College Achievement Awards. April 1990. Original tape."
      1 videocassette (U-matic): sound; 3/4 in. On label: "Tape 1. Time College Achievement Awards. April 19 1990. Original tape."
      1 videocassette (U-matic): sound; 3/4 in. On label: "Apr 1990. Tape 2. 1990. Time College Achievement Awards. Original taping-Award evening."
    - Bicentennial, 1976 (Offsite-box 2944, Folder 1-20)
      Events Time participated in to celebrate the United States 200-year anniversary included publication of a special issue; chartered cruise with guests from outside of the company to view Operation Sail 1976; reception at Gracie Mansion; and presentation of a Washington portrait to the White House.
    - Bicentennial [RESTRICTED], 1976 (Offsite-box R56)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Antitrust Conference, 1979 (Offsite-box 2944, Folder 21-31)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Antitrust Conference, 1979-1980 (Offsite-box 3096, Folder 1-24)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Antitrust Conference: Briefing Books, 1979 (Offsite-box 3115, Folder 1-3)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Board of Directors Meeting (Detroit, MI), 1977 (Offsite-box 3096, Folder 25-34)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Board of Directors Meeting (Detroit, MI), 1977 (Offsite-box 3097, Folder 1-2)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Cleveland/Pittsburgh Media Workshop (in New York), 1977 (Offsite-box 3257, Folder 1)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Detroit Media Seminar in New York, 1973 (Offsite-box 3097, Folder 3-5)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Divisional Meeting, 1970 (Offsite-box 3097, Folder 6)
      This two-day divisional meeting included the publisher, the business manager, and managers and directors from International Production, Marketing, Sales Development, Promotion, Advertising, and Circulation.
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Energy Conference '73, 1973 (Offsite-box 3097, Folder 7-31)
      The description from the files states that this conference organized collaboratively by Time, Fortune and Sports Illustrated included more than 60 government and business leaders, scientists and environmentalists concerned about the energy shortage, and main topics to cover were financing the nation's energy needs, closing the energy gap, and the Federal government's role in energy.
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Energy Conference '74, 1974 (Offsite-box 3097, Folder 32-37)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Energy Conference '74, 1974 (Offsite-box 3098, Folder 1-9)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Energy Conference '77, 1977 (Offsite-box 3098, Folder 10-43)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Energy Conference '77, 1977 (Offsite-box 3099, Folder 1-13)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Energy Conference '77: Briefing Books, 1977 (Offsite-box 3115, Folder 4-6)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Executive News Conference, 1989 (Offsite-box 3099, Folder 14)
      Taking place in Washington, D.C., this was an opportunity for presidents and other executives of major companies to act as "journalists in residence" while hearing from goverment officials such as the president's chief of staff and chairman of the Federal Reserve System along with correspondents and editors from Time through panel discussions. This event is sometimes referred to as the "Washington newstour" although there is no touring aspect.
      Additional records for this event are in Jean Gussenhoven's and Jelmir Lucas's files.
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Executive News Conference: Briefing Book Contents, 1989 (Offsite-box 2821, Folder 11-13)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Executive News Conference: Briefing Book Covers, 1989 (Offsite-box 2826, Folder 4-6)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Housing Industry Presidents' Conference 1968, 1966-1968 (Offsite-box 3099, Folder 15-26)
      1969 is stated to be the 15th annual conference although the earliest materials in the collection are from the 1968 event.
      The event was hosted by the Time Inc. board chairman, the Time publisher, and in later years the head of Time Inc. subsidiary lumbar company Temple Industries. Speakers included U.S. Secretary of Housing and Development and members of the Congress subcommittee on housing. It was attended by heads of builder and utility associations such as Edison Electric Institute, National Association of Home Builders, and American Plywood Association; builders like Fox Jacobs; suppliers like Reynolds Aluminum; heads of mortgage lenders; and board members from the Federal Reserve System. Topics discussed included housing policy, how to provide better housing for needy families, how to keep the mortgage market steady with adequate capital, and eliminating non-productive costs.
      Records include agendas and itineraries, invitations, participant lists, arrangements for accommodations and travel, conference programs and other distributed materials, copies of the post-conference publication, budgets and bills, and branded printed material. Includes correspondence and memoranda forwarded from forwards from director of government affairs John Pflieger and Heiskell
      There are no records for the event in 1975, 1979, or 1984.
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Housing Industry Presidents' Conference 1969 (Offsite-box 3100, Folder 1)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Housing Industry Presidents' Conference 1970 (Offsite-box 3100, Folder 2)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Housing Industry Presidents' Conference 1971 (Offsite-box 3100, Folder 3)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Housing Industry Presidents' Conference 1972 (Offsite-box 3100, Folder 4)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Housing Industry Presidents' Conference 1973 (Offsite-box 3100, Folder 5-8)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Housing Industry Presidents' Conference 1974 (Offsite-box 3100, Folder 9-20)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Housing Industry Presidents' Conference 1976 (Offsite-box 3100, Folder 21-23)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Housing Industry Presidents' Conference 1976 (Offsite-box 3101, Folder 1-25)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Housing Industry Presidents' Conference 1977 (Offsite-box 3101, Folder 26-47)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Housing Industry Presidents' Conference 1977 (Offsite-box 3102, Folder 1-25)
      This box includes copies of some speeches.
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Housing Industry Presidents' Conference 1978 (Offsite-box 3102, Folder 26-39)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Housing Industry Presidents' Conference 1978, 1978-1980 (Offsite-box 3103, Folder 1-31)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Housing Industry Presidents' Conference 1980, 1972-1976 (Offsite-box 3103, Folder 32)
      Records are all from earlier housing conferences and look like they were collected for reference.
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Housing Industry Presidents' Conference 1981 (Offsite-box 3103, Folder 33-51)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Housing Industry Presidents' Conference 1981 (Offsite-box 3104, Folder 1-22)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Housing Industry Presidents' Conference 1982 (Offsite-box 3104, Folder 23-33)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Housing Industry Presidents' Conference 1982 (Offsite-box 3105, Folder 1-25)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Housing Industry Presidents' Conference 1983 (Offsite-box 3105, Folder 26-47)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Housing Industry Presidents' Conference 1983 (Offsite-box 3106, Folder 1-12)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Housing Industry Presidents' Conference 1985 (Offsite-box 3106, Folder 13-19)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: International Area Directors Meeting, 1974-1975 (Offsite-box 3106, Folder 20-22)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: International Executive Conference, 1972 (Offsite-box 3106, Folder 23-28)
      Participants at this conference represented twenty Time advertising sales offices. Topics discussed included world economics, strategic advertising, travel advertising, and automotive advertising. Records include conference programs, conference facility arrangements, accommodations and travel arrangements, bills and budgets, itineraries, opening remarks, programming questionnaire, and arrangements for extracurricular activities.
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: International Executive Conference, 1972 (Offsite-box 3107, Folder 1-29)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: International Sales-Marketing Conference, 1974 (Offsite-box 3107, Folder 33-37)
      1 audio disc, analog, 33 1/2 rpm; 7 in. Title: "There's Never Been a Better Time."
      The disc includes "Ballad of the Branch Managers."
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Investment Capital Conference, 1975 (Offsite-box 3108, Folder 1-11)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Leadership Conference, 1975-1976 (Offsite-box 3108, Folder 12-41)
      Invitees to the conference included the two hundred young leaders featured in the 1974 Time Leadership Issue. Speakers included United States senators, the Secretary of Transportation, and Stanford University's president.
      Records include conference programs, conference facility arrangements, accommodations and travel arrangements, bills and budgets, itineraries, and speech transcripts. Also included
      Included is a file on Time's participation in the 1975 Major Magazines Leadership Study Presentations.
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Managers Meeting, 1978 (Offsite-box 3108, Folder 42-46)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Mid-America World Trade Conference, 1971 (Offsite-box 3108, Folder 47)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Promotion Conference, 1972 (Offsite-box 3108, Folder 48-49)
      The invitation describes this as "the first meeting ever held of the creative promotion and the public affairs people from all Time Inc. divisions, and as such is experimental." Early records refer to it as the "creative conference." The majority of the records are participant lists and logistical planning and not conference content.
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Promotion Conference, 1972 (Offsite-box 3109, Folder 1-6)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: The Role of Congress II, 1975 (Offsite-box 3257, Folder 2)
      Includes a report with some transcripts from a discussion between members of Congress and journalists in May 1975.
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: The Role of Congress II (binder cover), 1975 (Offsite-box 3260)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Sales Conference, 1978 (Offsite-box 3257, Folder 12-13)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Sales Conference, 1982 (Offsite-box 3257, Folder 29)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Sales Conference: "The Worlds of Time": Briefing Books, 1985? (Offsite-box 3115, Folder 7-8)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Sales Management Meeting, 1977 (Offsite-box 3257, Folder 3-11)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Sales Meeting 1972, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 3109, Folder 7-17)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Sales Meeting 1974 (Offsite-box 3109, Folder 18-19)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Sales Meeting 1976 (Offsite-box 3109, Folder 20)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Sales Meeting, 1978 (Offsite-box 3257, Folder 14-28)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Seminar on Military Manpower: Transcript, 1980 (Offsite-box 3109, Folder 21)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Seminar on Soviet-American Relations: Briefing Book, 1980 (Offsite-box 3109, Folder 22)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Taxation Conference: Briefing Book, 1978 (Offsite-box 3115, Folder 9)
      This conference was held in Washington, D.C. to discuss federal tax policy and capital formation with government officials, economists, and industry, banking and labor executives.
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Thanat Khoman Tour and Dinner, 1965-1966 (Offsite-box 3140)
      Foreign Minister of Thailand Thanat Khoman had a nine-day visit to the United States in May 1965 at the invitation of Time Inc. President James Linen. The invitation was prompted by a session with Thanat during the 1965 Time Newstour of Southeast Asia. His visit included discussions with several groups on U.S. policy in Southeast Asia and a dinner hosted by the newstour participants. Records include the planning of the dinner and itineraries in the various cities along with a report written by Thanat.
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Time/Concorde, 1970 (Offsite-box 3109, Folder 23-25)
      This is a short conference to Bristol and Paris for business executives, marketing managers, and advertising supervisors to see the Concorde and meet the people responsible for designing, building, and marketing it. Records include participant information, a copy of the conference program, and photographs of the event.
      1 audiotape reel (Longplay LP15): analog, 3 3/4 ips; 5 3/4 in., 1/4 in. tape. On container: "[Dinner] speech - [Ledayen] Feb. 7. 70 copy - speed 9.5 cm/s. 1/2 track."
      1 audiotape reel (Longplay LP35): analog; 5 in., 1/4 in. tape. On container: "Transcribed. Feb. 7, 70- Seminar tape. Speed [4.75cm] Both _______. Mr. Shaffer."
      1 audiotape reel: analog; 5 in., 1/4 in. tape. On container: "Feb 7, 70. Lunch speech tape. Speed 4.75cm. 1 1/2 track [used] ___."
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Time/Concorde Conference, 1970 (Offsite-box 3110, Folder 1-6)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Time/European Conference, 1973 (Offsite-box 3110, Folder 7-28)
      Participants are European business executives. Topics discussed include monetary reform, world trade, world energy, and world economy. Records include agendas, the briefing book, participant list,
      1 audiocassette (Agfa): analog; 3 7/8 x 2 1/2 in., 1/8 in. tape. Inside envelope addressed to D. Schnitzer.
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Time Inc. Second Creative Conference, 1978 (Offsite-box 2855)
      The first conference of this type may have been the 1972 Promotion Conference. Records include conference programs and a scrapbook of this conference held at Harvard University.
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Time in New York, 1978 (Offsite-box 3111, Folder 1-10)
      A short conference of visiting European advertising and marketing executives. Records include lists of speakers, intineraries, and planning for the conference space, accommodations, and travel.
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Time/Russia Conference, 1973 (Offsite-box 3111, Folder 11-13)
      This was a meeting, taking place in Russia, of the international management of Time, all from the publishing, advertising, and sales side. Within the larger meeting was the Interantional Advertising Sales Directors Conference. Records include the conference program and Irina Bagration's planning binder.
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Time/Russia Conference: Irina Bagration Binder: Original Cover, 1973 (Offsite-box 2826, Folder 7)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Time/747 Conference, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 3111, Folder 14-20)
      This was a short trip to Seattle to see the new Boeing aircraft followed up by a panel discussion. Participants were advertising and merchandising executives.
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Time/SuperJet Conference, 1971 (Offsite-box 3111, Folder 21-24)
      Located in Deauville, France and hosted by Time Inc. president James Shepley with 175 guests from the United States, Europe and the Middle East this conference included aircraft tours and briefings, viewing the Paris Air Show, and addresses from executives at the six major airlines of the time along with the U.S. Transportation Secretary and F.A.A. Administrator. Records include press releases, participant lists, photographs from the event, and itineraries.
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: Time/SuperJet Conference, 1971 (Offsite-box 3112, Folder 1-17)
    - Conferences/Meetings/Seminars: 200 Young Leaders Conference (unrealized), 1976 (Offsite-box 3112, Folder 18)
    - Dinners/Lunches: Bulova Luncheon, 1977 (Offsite-box 3258, Folder 1)
    - Dinners/Lunches: Greenspan, Alan Dinner, 1974 (Offsite-box 3112, Folder 19-20)
      1 audiotape reel: analog; 7 in., 1/4 in. tape. On container: "Alan Greenspan Dinner Oct. 23, 1974. 8th fl. Auditorium."
    - Dinners/Lunches: Hosted by Board Luncheon: "Now's the Time", 1975 (Offsite-box 3112, Folder 21)
    - Dinners/Lunches: Kissinger, Henry Dinner at the United Nations Plaza, 1977 (Offsite-box 3258, Folder 2-6)
    - Dinners/Lunches: Linen, James: Golf Lunch, 1976 (Offsite-box 3112, Folder 22)
    - Dinners/Lunches: Linen, James: King of Thailand Dinner, 1967 (Offsite-box 3112, Folder 23)
    - Dinners/Lunches: McMahon, William (Prime Minister of Australia) Lunch, 1971 (Offsite-box 3112, Folder 24)
    - Dinners/Lunches: Rabin, Yitzhak (Prime Minister of Israel) Dinner, 1976 (Offsite-box 3112, Folder 25)
    - Dinner/Lunches: Scott, John Dinner, 1972 (Offsite-box 3112, Folder 26)
    - Funeral/Memorial/Tribute: Luce, Henry R., 1967 (Offsite-box 3112, Folder 27-34)
      Includes copies of the tribute book, programs from the funeral and memorial, news clippings, and correspondence regarding the special magazine section.
    - Parties/Receptions: American Trucking Associations, Inc. Cocktail Party, 1971 (Offsite-box 3112, Folder 35)
    - Parties/Receptions: Ballet Evening, 1976 (Offsite-box 3112, Folder 36)
    - Parties/Receptions: Golf Outing / Time World Challenge Cup, 1970 (Offsite-box 3113, Folder 1-4)
      This event may be one of the early Invitationals which were annual invitation-only sports competition events organized by the magazines' Advertising Sales Departments and held at the Maidstone Club in East Hamptons, NY.
    - Parties/Receptions: Meadowbrook Music Festival, 1972 (Offsite-box 3113, Folder 5-7)
    - Parties/Receptions: Mexico City Reception for New Advertising Representative, 1972 (Offsite-box 3113, Folder 8-9)
    - Parties/Receptions: Meyers, Jack and Bob Barr Party for Staff Changes, 1972 (Offsite-box 3113, Folder 10)
    - Parties/Receptions: Sadat, Anwar (President of Egypt), 1975 (Offsite-box 3113, Folder 11)
    - Parties/Receptions: Time International Reception, 1977 (Offsite-box 3258, Folder 7)
    - Political Conventions: 1972: Democratic (Offsite-box 3113, Folder 12-19)
    - Political Conventions: 1972: Republican, 1971 (Offsite-box 3113, Folder 20-29)
    - Political Conventions: 1984, 1980-1984 (Offsite-box 4184, Folder 16)
    - Political Conventions: 1988 (Offsite-box 3113, Folder 30)